抱歉
Sorry.
她到哪儿去了
Where did she go ?
什么
What ?
你是谁
Who are you ?
但是…
But. . .
我在哪儿
Where am I ?
什么
What ?
这到底是什么地方
What the hell is this place ?
什么
What ? !
神秘博士2006圣诞特别篇
逃跑新娘
你不可能做到 我不…
You can't do that, I wasn't. . .
我们还在航行中
We're in flight.
这理论上是不可能的 你怎么…
That is physically impossible, how did. . . ?
告诉我这是哪儿
Tell me where I am.
我命令你 立刻告诉我这是哪儿
I demand you tell me, right now, where am I ?
在塔迪斯里
Inside the TARDIS.
哪儿 -塔迪斯
The what ? -The TARDIS.
What ? -The TARDIS.
塔什么 -它叫塔迪斯
The what ? -It's called the TARDIS.
根本就没有这个词 你就胡编乱造吧
That's not a proper word. You're just saying things.
你怎么进来的
How did you get in here ?
很明显你绑架了我
Well, obviously, when you kidnapped me.
谁干的 是谁雇的你
Who was it ? Who's paying you ?
是不是奈瑞斯
Was it Nerys ?
哦 天哪 她终于对我下手了
Oh, my God, she's finally got me back.
这一定是奈瑞斯一手操纵的
This has got Nerys written all over it.
谁是奈瑞斯
Who the hell is Nerys ?
你最好的朋友
Your best friend !
等等 你为什么穿成这样
Wait a minute. What are you dressed like that for ?
我正要去打保龄球 你以为呢 呆子
I'm going ten-pin bowling. . . Why do you think, dumbo !
我正走在红地毯上 我一生都在等待着一刻
I was halfway up the aisle ! I've waited all my life for this.
就差几秒钟了 然后你
I was just seconds away, and then you. . .
我不知道 你迷晕了我之类的
I dunno, you drug me or something.
我什么也没做
I haven't done anything.
我要报警抓你
I will have the police on you.
我和我丈夫 只要他一成为我丈夫
Me and my husband, as soon as he is my husband,
我们一定告到你倾家荡产
we're gonna sue the living backside off you !
不 等等 等等 别…
No, wait a minute, wait a minute, don't. . .
你在太空里
You're in space,
外太空
outer space.
这是我的…
This is my. . .
宇宙飞船
space-ship.
它叫塔迪斯
It's called the TARDIS.
我怎么能呼吸
How am I breathing ?
塔迪斯在保护我们
The TARDIS is protecting us.
你是谁
Who are you ?
我是博士 你呢
I'm The Doctor. You ?
多娜
Donna.
人类
Human ?
是的
Yeah.
还有别的选项吗
Is that optional ?
对我来说是的
It is for me.
你是外星人
You're an alien ?
是啊
Yeah.
门开着真冷
It's freezing with these doors open.
我不明白 我实在是不明白
I don't understand it, and I understand everything !
这不可能发生
This can't happen.
没有哪个人类能锁定塔迪斯
There is no way a human being can lock itself onto the TARDIS
并传送进来 一定是…
and transport itself inside. It must be. . .
一定是临时场中某种亚原子连接
It must be some sort of subatomic connection, something in the temporal field.
也许是你被扯进了一个时间壳阵列中
Maybe something pulling you into an alignment with the Chronon shell,
也许是什么东西把你的DNA结合到了内部矩阵上
Maybe something macrobinding your DNA with the interior matrix. . .
也许是某种基因…
Maybe a genetic. . .
这是为什么
What was that for ?
送我回教堂
Get me to the church !
好吧 反正我也不想留你在这儿
Right ! Fine, I don't want you here anyway !
婚礼在哪儿举行
Where is this wedding ?
圣玛利教堂 港口大道 奇斯威克区 伦敦 英国
St Mary's, Haven Road, Chiswick. London, England.
地球 太阳系
Earth. The Solar System.
我就知道
I knew it.
别装得这么无辜 我不是第一个 对吧
Acting all innocent, I'm not the first, am I ?
你绑架过多少女人
How many women have you abducted ?
那是我朋友的
That's my friend's.
那她在哪儿 出去走太空步了
Where is she then, popped out for a spacewalk ?
她走了
She's gone.
去哪儿了
Gone where ?
我失去了她
I lost her.
那你赶紧把我也失去吧
Well, you can hurry up and lose me !
你说的失去是什么意思
How do you mean, "lost" ?
好了 奇斯威克
Right ! Chiswick !
不 她没有逃跑
No, she didn't run away.
这不是精神过敏的问题 她真的消失了
We're not talking jitters, she literally vanished,
去屋子里找找
now go and check the house.
哦 安吉拉 别一点用都没有 机灵点
Oh, Angelica, that's not helping, is it ? Now smarten up.
兰斯 有消息吗
Lance, any sign ?
我到处找遍了 她到底去哪儿了
I've looked all round. Where the hell did she go ?
卖弄罢了 她就是这种人
Showing off. That's what she is.
她开学第一天就咬了别人 被遣送回家
First day at school, she was sent home for biting.
这回严重得多 她还从没玩过失踪呢
It's a bit more serious than that. She's never disappeared before.
她不是失踪
She didn't disappear !
是个恶作剧 只是想引起大家注意的小把戏罢了
It's a trick, it's one of her silly little "look at me" party pieces.
万一她死了呢
Oh, what if she's dead ?
哦 别这么说
Oh, don't say that.
我说的是圣玛丽大教堂
I said St Mary's.
你是什么火星人啊 这是哪儿
What sort of Martian are you ? Where's this ?
塔迪斯好像出了点问题 它好像在
Something's wrong with her. The TARDIS, like she's. . .
重新校准
recalibrating !
她在整理
She's digesting.
怎么了 出什么问题了
What is it ? What's wrong ?
多娜
Donna,
这可能是什么引起的
is there anything that might have caused this ?
你是不是做了什么 有没有和外星人接触过
Anything you might've done ? Any sort of alien contact ?
如果你还处于危险中 我不能任你离开
I can't let you go wandering off, not if you're dangerous.
你有没有见到天空中奇怪的光
Have you seen lights in the sky,
或者接触到了什么特别的东西
or did you touch something, like, something different,
一些奇怪的东西 比如古怪的金属制品
something strange, like something made out of a funny sort of metal. . .
你要和谁结婚 你确定他是人类吗
Who are you getting married to ? You sure he's human ?
他该不会是个头上有拉链的胖子吧
He's not a bit overweight with a zip round his forehead, is he ?
多娜
Donna !
Donna ?
别管我 我只是想结婚
Leave me alone. I just want to get married.
回塔迪斯去
Come back to the TARDIS.
决不 那个亭子太古怪了
No way, that box is too weird.
只是里面大了一点 仅此而已
It's bigger on the inside, that's all.
哦 仅此而已
Oh, that's all !
3点10分 我要迟到了
Ten past three, I'm gonna miss it.
你能不能打个电话 告诉他们你在哪里
Can't you phone them, tell them where you are ?
我要怎么打
How do I do that ?
你没有手机吗
Haven't you got a mobile ?
我穿着婚纱 它没有口袋
I'm in my wedding dress. It doesn't have pockets.
谁会有口袋 你见过带口袋的婚纱吗
Who has pockets ? Have you ever seen a bride with pockets ?
我试穿的时候 就忘了加一句 "给我加个口袋"
When I went to my fitting, the one thing I forgot to say was, "Give me pockets !"
你要嫁的人叫什么名字
This man you're marrying, what's his name ?
兰斯
Lance.
祝你好运 兰斯
Good luck, Lance.
嘿 你这愚蠢的火星人 休想阻止我结婚 见鬼去吧
Oi ! No stupid Martian is gonna stop me from getting married. To hell with you !
我不是…我不是从火星来的
I'm not. . . I'm not from Mars.
出租车
Taxi !
他的顶灯还亮着
He had his light on !
那儿还有一辆
There's another one.
出租车
Taxi ! Oi !
又有一辆
There's one.
每辆都空着 他们为什么不停车
Why aren't they stopping ?
他们以为我穿着化妆舞会的衣服
They think I'm in fancy dress.
少喝几杯吧 亲爱的
Lay off the sauce, darlin' !
他们以为我喝多了
They think I'm drunk.
你骗不了人的 哥们
You're fooling no-one, mate !
他们以为我男扮女装
They think I'm in drag !
等等 等等
Hold on, hold on.
圣玛丽大教堂 奇斯威克 就停港口街
St Mary's, in Chiswick, just off Haven Road.
情况紧急 我要去结婚 快点
It's an emergency, I'm getting married, just. . . Hurry up !
那你要破费了 亲爱的 今天双倍收费
That'll cost you, sweetheart, double rates today.
天呐 你有没有钱
Oh, my God. Have you got any money ?
没有 你呢
Um. No. Haven't you ?
没口袋
Pockets !
跟你老妈去收双倍吧
And that goes double for your mother !
我会跟他算账的 我记下他的车牌了
I'll have him. I've got his number, I'll have him.
说什么圣诞精神
Talk about the Christmas spirit.
现在是圣诞节吗
Is it Christmas ?
也许火星上不是 但这里今天是平安夜
Well, duh ! Maybe not on Mars, but here it's Christmas Eve.
电话亭
Phone box !
我们可以让对方付费
We can reverse the charges.
你怎么会在平安夜结婚
How come you're getting married on Christmas Eve ?
受不了了 我讨厌圣诞节
Can't bear it, I hate Christmas.
我要去摩纳哥度蜜月 享受阳光和美景
Honeymoon, Morocco, sunshine, lovely.
我要拨什么号 好多年没用过了 要拨什么 100
What's the operator ? I've not done this in years. What do you dial, 100 ?
直接拨 -你做了什么
Just call direct. What did you do ?
一些…火星的东西 快打电话 我去弄钱
Something. . .Martian. Now phone ! I'll get money.
快接电话
Oh, answer the phone !
喂 我没电了 谁有充电器
Hello ? Oh, now the battery's gone dead, has anyone got a charger ?
能不能查查旅馆
Could you try the hotel ?
喂 喂
Hello ? Hello ?
维克 你的电话能用吗 我的没电了
Vikram, is your phone working? mine is run out.
一个婚礼还没完
I've got one wedding about to arrive
另一个婚礼又来了
and another wedding refusing to leave,
所以没错 我认为这该交给警察
So yes, I do think it IS a police matter.
妈妈 别打电话了 听我说
Mum, get off the phone and listen !
我在…
I'm in. . .
天呐 我不知道我在哪儿
Oh, my God, I don't know where I am.
是一条街…有个WH·史密斯店
It's a street. . . and there's a WH Smith.
但绝对是地球
But it's definitely Earth !
打扰一下 我求求你
Excuse me. I'm begging you,
我要结婚了 快要迟到了
I'm getting married, and I'm late,
我只要借十磅 我保证会还您的
and I just need to borrow a tenner, and I'll pay you back, I promise.
今天是圣诞节啊
and It's Christmas.
出租车
Taxi !
圣玛利教堂 奇斯威克区
St Mary's, Chiswick.
谢谢你帮倒忙了 太空人 我们法庭见
Thanks for nothing, spaceman ! I'll see you in court !
多娜
Donna !
等我们到了我会把剩余的给你
I'll give you the rest when we get there.
我看起来一团糟
Oh, I look a mess.
开快点
Hurry up !
等一下 我说奇斯威克区
Hold on a minute, I said Chiswick !
你错过那个拐弯了 你听见了吗
You've missed the turning. Excuse me ?
刚刚应该转弯 后面那儿
We should've turned off, back there.
我们走错路了
We're going the wrong way !
你到底在干嘛
What the hell are you doing ?
我参加婚礼要迟到了
I'm late for the wedding.
我自己的婚礼 你听到了没
My own wedding, do you get that ?
掉头 立刻把车掉头
Turn around ! Turn this cab around right now !
你是聋子还是什么
Are you deaf or what ?
哦 天哪
Oh, my God.
救命
Help me !
救救我 救救我
Help me ! Help me !
救命
Help me !
救命 放我出去
Help me ! Get me out !
救救我
Help me !
救救我 我的司机是个机器人
Help me, I'm being driven by a robot !
乖一点
Behave !
你在跟我开玩笑吧
You are kidding me.
开门
Open the door !
什么
Do what ?
把门打开
Open the door !
打不开 锁上了
I can't ! It's locked !
圣诞老人是机器人
Santa's a robot !
多娜 把门打开
Donna, open the door.
为什么 -你得跳过来
What for ?! You've got to jump !
你要我表演特技吗 我本来是去结婚的
Am I blinking flip jumping ! I'm supposed to be getting married !
听我说 你必须跳过来
Listen to me, you've got to jump !
我才不在高速公路上跳车
I'm not jumping on a motorway !
不管那是什么东西 它需要你
Whatever that thing is, it needs you.
不管它要你干什么 肯定不是好事
And whatever it needs you for, it's not good !
快点
Now come on !
我还穿着婚纱
I'm in my wedding dress !
是 你看上去真漂亮 快跳
Yes, you look lovely. Come on !
我不行
I can't do it !
相信我
Trust me.
你对她也是这么说的吗
Is that what you said to her ?
你的朋友 你失去的那个
Your friend. The one you lost.
她相信你吗
Did she trust you ?
是的 她相信 而且她没死
Yes, she did. And she is not dead.
她活得好好的
She is so alive.
快跳
Now jump !
有趣的是 作为一艘飞船 它很少那样飞
Funny thing is, for a spaceship, she doesn't do that much flying.
最好让它休息几个钟头 你没事吧
We'd better give her a couple of hours. You all right ?
不要紧
Doesn't matter.
我们错过婚礼了吗
Did we miss it ?
是的
Yeah.
你可以重新定个日子
Well, you can book another date.
当然可以
Course we can.
你仍然可以度蜜月
You've still got the honeymoon.
现在只是个节日了
It's just a holiday, now.
是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
抱歉
Sorry.
不是你的错
It's not your fault.
哦 这可是个转变
Oh. That's a change.
真希望你有时间机器
Wish you had a time machine.
我们就可以回去纠正一切了
Then we could go back and get it right.
嗯 是啊
Um, yeah, yeah.
但是
But. . .
即使我有 也没法沿个人时间线回到过去
even if I did, I couldn't go back on someone's personal timeline.
显而易见
Apparently.
天哪 你真瘦 老鼠穿着都嫌小
God, you're skinny. This wouldn't fit a rat.
你最好戴上这个
Oh, and you'd better put this on.
你非得戳人痛处
Oh, d'you have to rub it in ?
那些生物能追踪你
Those creatures can trace you.
这是生物抑制器 能把你隐藏起来
This is a biodamper, should keep you hidden.
我用这枚戒指 将你隐藏
With this ring. . .I thee biodamp.
不论好坏 祸福与共
For better or for worse.
那些圣诞机器人 它们的目的是什么
So come on, then -robot Santas, what are they for ?
那是低级的清道夫
Your basic roboscavenger.
圣诞老人只是伪装 融入环境
The Father Christmas stuff is just a disguise. Trying to blend in.
去年圣诞节我也遇到它们了
I met them last Christmas.
怎么 发生了什么事
Why, what happened then ?
巨大的太空飞船
Great big spaceship,
盘旋在伦敦上空 你没注意到
hovering over London ? You didn't notice ?
我那时有点醉
I had a bit of a hangover.
我那时是在鲍威尔庄园过的圣诞 和…
I spent Christmas Day over there, the Powell Estate, with this. . .
一家人
.family.
我的朋友和她的家人 他们
My friend, she had this family. Well, they. . .
然而
Still.
现在不在了
Gone now.
你那个朋友 她是谁
Your friend. Who was she ?
问题是那些伪装的机器佣兵 想从你这儿得到什么
The question is, what do camouflage robot mercenaries want with you ?
你又是怎么进的塔迪斯 我实在不明白
And how did you get inside the TARDIS ? I dunno. . .
你的工作是什么
What's your job ?
我是个秘书
I'm a secretary.
奇怪了 你又不特别 也不强大
Weird. I mean, you're not special, you're not powerful,
不聪明 也不重要
you're not clever, you're not important. . .
你那个朋友 在她离开之前 有没有给你一耳光
This friend of yours, just before she left, did she punch you in the face ?
别扫描我了
Stop bleeping me !
哪种秘书
What kind of secretary ?
我在H.C.克莱门斯工作
I'm at HC Clements.
我就是在那里遇到兰斯的 我还是临时工
That's where I met Lance. I was temping.
我觉得 那真的是如梦幻一般
I mean, it was all a bit posh, really.
过去两年都呆在双层玻璃的公司里
I'd spent the last two years at a double glazing firm.
我想我永远不会适应这里
Well, I thought, I'm never going to fit in here.
然后他给我泡了一杯咖啡
And then he made me a cup of coffee.
我是说这不可能发生
I mean, that just doesn't happen.
没人会给秘书倒咖啡
Nobody gets the secretaries a coffee.
而兰斯 他是人力资源主管 他不需要为我费心
And Lance, he's the Head of HR, he didn't need to bother with me.
他人很好 也很风趣
But he was nice, he was funny.
她没有那么糟 -她就是
She isn't that bad. She is
结果他也认为其他人都很讨厌
And it turns out he thought everyone else was really snotty too.
这就是我和他的开始
So, that's how it started, me and him.
就是因为一杯咖啡
One cup of coffee and that was it.
那是什么时候的事
When was this ?
六个月以前
Six months ago.
现在结婚有点早吧
Bit quick, to get married.
是他坚持的
Well. . .he insisted.
你能娶我吗
Will you marry me ?
他不停的烦我
And he nagged and he nagged me.
哦 考虑考虑吧
Oh, just think about it.
我们肯定是很好的一对
We'd make a great couple,
我可以把那条狗扔掉
and I'd get rid of the dog,
然后我们打扫一下后面的卧室
and we could do out that back bedroom.
他把我耗烦了 最后我只好投降
And he just wore me down. And then finally I just gave in.
求你
Please.
哦 求求你
Oh, please.
求你 求你 求你 求你 求你 求你
Please, please, please, please, please, please.
H.C.克莱门斯是干嘛的
What does HC Clements do ?
安全系统
Oh, security systems.
你知道 密码门锁 ID卡之类的东西
Y'know, entry codes, ID cards, that sort of thing.
要我说 只不过是锁匠铺起了个好听的名字罢了
Ask me, it's a posh name for a locksmith's.
钥匙
Keys. . .
总之我的自我介绍够长了
Anyway, enough of my CV.
现在是面对结果的时候了
Come on, it's time to face the consequences.
哦 这太丢脸了
Oh, this is gonna be so shaming.
你可以负责解释 火星人
You can do the explaining, Martian Boy.
这个…我不是从火星上来的
Yeah, I'm not from Mars.
哦 我还办了一个盛大的婚礼酒会
Oh, I had this great big reception all planned.
大家肯定心都碎了…
Everyone's going to be heartbroken. .
我不在 你们还是开了酒会
You had the reception without me ?
多娜 你出什么事了
Donna, what happened to you ?
我不在 你们还玩的那么高兴
You had the reception without me ?
嗨 我是博士
Hello, I'm The Doctor.
我不在 他们照样开了酒会
They had the reception without me !
是啊 我看到了
Yes, I gathered.
都已经付钱了 为什么不开
Well, it was all paid for, why not ?
谢谢 奈瑞斯
Thank you, Nerys.
那我们该怎么办
Well, what were we supposed to do ?
我收到了你那个愚蠢的消息
I got your silly little message in the end.
"我在地球上" 真有趣
"I'm on Earth" ? ! Very funny.
但到底发生了什么
But what the hell happened ?
你消失了 怎么做到的
You vanished ! How did you do it ?
是什么恶作剧 我知道肯定是幻像…
What's the trick, cos I know it's an illusion. . .
♪我曾彷徨,我曾迷失♪
♪I have wandered, I have rambled♪
♪我穿过了高原♪
♪I have crossed the stratosphere♪
♪我见过太多的难题♪
♪I have seen a mess of problems♪
♪我渴望消失♪
♪That I long to disappear♪
♪现在我痛苦的心♪
♪Now all I have's this anguished heart♪
（搜索"H.C.克莱门斯"）
♪因为你也已经消失了♪
♪For you have vanished too♪
♪噢 我的女孩 我的女孩 我可爱的女孩♪
♪Oh, my girl My girl, my precious girl♪
♪我该做什么♪
♪Just what is this man to do ?♪
♪抱着我 我可爱的女孩 来吧,带我回家♪
♪So reel me in, my precious girl Come on, take me home♪
（H.C.克莱门斯 独资企业 火炬木）
♪因为我已经厌倦了旅行♪
♪Cos my body's tired of travelling♪
♪我的心不想徘徊♪
♪And my heart don't wish to roam♪
♪带上我 我的宝贝 来吧 带我回家♪
♪Yeah, reel me in, my precious girl Come on, take me home♪
♪因为我已经厌倦了旅行♪
♪Cos my body's tired of travelling♪
♪我的心不想徘徊♪
♪And my heart don't wish to roam♪
♪不 不♪
♪No, no♪
♪带上我♪
♪Well, you took me in♪
♪你偷走了我的心 我不能再到处游走♪
♪You stole my heart I cannot roam no more♪
♪因为爱 它留在你那里 海浪也冲不走它♪
♪Cos love, it stays within you It doesn't wash up on a shore♪
♪这个斗士 忘了每个痛伤♪
♪And a fighting man forgets each cut♪
♪每次碰撞 每个瘀伤 每次受伤♪
♪Each knock, each bruise, each fall♪
♪但战士不能忘记…♪
♪But a fighting man cannot forget. . .♪♪
我录下了整个过程
Oh, I taped the whole thing.
他们都看到了
They've all had a look.
他们说把这个卖给《骗中骗》节目
They said sell it to You've Been Framed.
我说 上新闻频道还差不多
I said, more like the news !
就这里
Here we are.
这不可能…再放一遍
It can't be. . . Play it again.
真聪明 不错的把戏
Clever, mind. Good trick, I'll give her that.
我还鼓掌来着
I was clapping.
但看上去像…
But that looks like. . .
Huon粒子
Huon particles.
那是什么
What's that, then ?
那不可能 那…
That's impossible. That's. . .
太古老了 Huon能量早就不存在了
Ancient. Huon energy doesn't exist any more,
已经几十亿年了
not for billions of years.
它如此古老…
It's so old that. . .
因此无法被生物抑制器隐藏起来
It can't be hidden by a biodamper !
多娜
Donna !
多娜 它们发现你了
Donna ! They've found you !
你说过我是安全的
You said I was safe !
抑制器无效 我们得让大家出去
The biodamper doesn't work. We've got to get everyone out.
天哪 我家人都在这里
My God, it's all my family.
从后门出去
Out the back door !
还是算了
Maybe not !
我们被困住了
We're trapped !
圣诞树 -它们怎么了
Christmas trees. What about them ?
它们会杀人 快离开那些树
They kill. Get away from the trees !
离开圣诞树 大家离开那些圣诞树
Get away from the Christmas trees ! Everyone get away from the trees !
兰斯…把音乐关了 听我说
Lance. . . ! Turn the music off. Listen to me
远离那些树
away from the trees.
离那些树远点
Stay away from the trees !
哦天哪 那个男的是白痴吗
Oh, for God's sake, the man's an idiot.
一棵圣诞树能干什么…
What harm is a Christmas tree gonna. . . ?
哦
Oh.
喂 圣诞老人 给你们一点建议
Oi ! Santa ! Word of advice.
如果你们要攻击一个带着音速起子的人
If you're attacking a man with a sonic screwdriver. . .
千万别让他靠近音响
don't let him near the sound system.
没事了 斯坦 都没事了
It's all right, Stan, you'll be all right.
麦克 康妮
Michael ? Connie ?
哦 苏妮 来帮点忙
Oh, Sunita, do something useful.
那是什么 他们是什么
What is it ? What were they ?
别唠叨了 帮帮他们
Just stop wittering, just help 'em !
看看这个 装饰品的遥控装置
Look at that. Remote control for the decorations
还有个机器人的遥控器
but there's a second remote control for the robots.
它们不再是清道夫了 有人控制了它们
They're not scavengers any more. Someone's taken possession.
别管那个了 你是个医生 有人受伤了
Don't mind all that, you're a doctor. People have been hurt.
不 它们想要你活着 看这个 都没有激活
Nah, they wanted you alive, look. They're not active now.
都一样 你可以来帮忙的
All the same, you could help.
你得考虑大局
You've got to think of the bigger picture.
还有信号
There's still a signal !
多娜 他是谁
Donna, who is he ?
这个人是谁
Who is that man ?
有人在背后操作这些机器人
There's someone behind this, directing the roboforms.
但为什么是我 我做了什么
But why is it me ? What have I done ?
找到控制者 我们就找到答案了 哦
Find the controller, and we'll find that out. Ooh.
在上面
It's up there.
在天上的东西
Something in the sky.
聪明 聪明 聪明的孩子
Clever, clever, clever boy.
吃掉你这个小点心
Eat you up all snicker-snacker,
小旅行者
little travelling man. . .
他会来找我的 带着漂亮的新娘一起来
He shall come to me, and the beautiful bride.
秘密将会解封
Such secrets to unlock.
我今晚就会降临
I shall descend this night.
降临到这个地球上来
I shall descend upon this Earth
大放异彩
and shine !
我失去信号了 我们得去你的办公室
I've lost the signal ! We've got to get to your office.
H.C.克莱门斯 我觉得一切都起源于那里
I think that's where it all started. Lance ! Is it Lance ?
兰斯 是不是兰斯
兰斯 能带我们一程吗
Lance, can you give me a lift ?
对于你们可能只是个修锁公司
To you lot this might just be a locksmith's,
但H.C.克莱门斯是23年前由火炬木研究院建立的
but HC Clements was bought up 23 years ago by the Torchwood Institute.
他们是谁
Who are they ?
他们是金丝雀码头之战的挑起者
They were behind the Battle of Canary Wharf.
赛博人入侵
Cyberman invasion.
伦敦上空的戴立克
Skies over London full of Daleks ?
我当时在西班牙
Skies over London full of Daleks ? I was in Spain.
西班牙也有赛博人啊
They had Cybermen in Spain.
我在潜水
Scuba-diving.
你为什么总是错过大事
That big picture, you keep on missing it.
火炬木被摧毁了 但H.C.克莱门斯仍在运营
Torchwood was destroyed, but HC Clements stayed in business.
我猜是有人接管了这里
I think someone else came in and took over the operation.
但他们想从我这里得到什么
But what do they want with me ?
不知何故 你服用了Huon能量
Somehow, you've been dosed with Huon energy.
这就是个问题
And that's a problem,
因为Huon粒子自从黑暗时代起就不存在了
because Huon energy hasn't existed since the dark times.
现在唯一能找到Huon粒子的地方 是塔迪斯的心脏
The only place you'd find a Huon particle now is a remnant in the heart of the TARDIS.
你瞧 那就是这样发生的
Y'see, that's what happened.
比如说那是塔迪斯 那是你
Say that's the TARDIS, and that's you.
你体内的粒子被激活了 粒子互相吸引 然后变
The particles inside you activated, the particles magnetised and whap !
你就这样被拉进了塔迪斯
You were pulled inside the TARDIS.
我是杯子里的一支铅笔
I'm a pencil inside a mug. Yes, you are. 4H. Sums you up.
好吧 是的 4H的 和你一模一样
兰斯 H.C.克莱门斯都在忙些什么
Lance, what was HC Clements working on ?
有什么最高机密 特别行动 禁止进入之类的
Anything top secret, special operations, do not enter ?
我不知道 我只负责人员 我不是项目经理…
I'm in charge of personnel, I wasn't project manager. . .
我干嘛要解释 我们到底在说什么
Why am I even explaining myself ?
你们是做钥匙的 那就是重点
You make keys, that's the point
看看这个
and look at this !
我们在三楼
We're on the third floor.
接待处下面是个地下室 对吧
Underneath reception, there's a basement, yes ?
那地下室下面怎么会还有一层呢
How come on the lift there's a button marked lower basement ?
这一整层都不在设计图纸里
There's a whole floor which doesn't exist on the official plans.
下面有什么
What's down there ?
你认为这幢楼有个秘密的楼层
Are you telling me this building's got a secret floor ?
不 我在告诉你这里有个秘密楼层
No, I'm showing you this building's got a secret floor.
需要钥匙
It needs a key.
我不需要
I don't.
好了 谢谢你们二位 我能搞定这个 再见
Right, thanks, you two, I can handle this. See you later.
不行 火星人 你总是救我的命
No chance. You're the man who keeps saving my life.
我不会让你离开我的视线的
I ain't letting you out of my sight.
下去了
Going down !
兰斯
Lance !
也许我该去叫警察
Maybe I should go to the police. . .
进来
Inside !
遵守婚礼的誓言 -还用说吗
To honour and obey. Tell me about it, mate.
喂
Oi !
新娘接近了
The bride approaches.
她是我的钥匙
She is my key.
我们在哪里
Where are we ?
这里在进行什么
What goes on down here ?
我们会知道的
Let's find out.
你觉得克莱门斯先生知道这个地方吗
D'you think Mr Clements knows about this place ?
神秘的H.C.克莱门斯 我认为就是他安排的
The mysterious HC Clements. Oh, I think he's part of it.
瞧 交通工具
Oh, look. Transport !
在这儿等着 我打探一下情况
Wait here, I just need to get my bearings.
什么都别做
Don't do anything.
你最好会回来
You'd better come back.
我想甩也甩不掉你的
Couldn't get rid of you if I tried.
多娜 你认真想过这个吗
Donna, have you thought about this, properly ?
我是说 这很严肃的
I mean, this is serious !
我们到底该怎么办
What the hell are we gonna do ?
我觉得七月好了
Oh, I thought July.
泰晤士河的防洪闸 就在我们上面
Thames Flood Barrier ! Right on top of us.
火炬木偷偷进来然后在地下建造了这地方
Torchwood snuck in and built this place underneath.
什么 伦敦主要地标下面藏着一个秘密基地
What, there's, like, a secret base hidden underneath a major London landmark ?
我知道 真是闻所未闻
I know. Unheard of.
哦 看看这个
Oooh, look at this.
太惊人了
Stunning !
这是用来干嘛的
What does it do ?
产出粒子 等等…
Particle extrusion. Hold on. . .
真厉害
Brilliant !
他们一直在制造Huon粒子
They've been manufacturing Huon particles.
我们的人消灭了Huon粒子 拆散了其原子结构
My people got rid of Huons, they unravelled the atomic structure.
你们的人 他们是谁
Your people? Who are they ?
你代表哪家公司
What company d'you represent ?
哦 我是个自由职业者
Oh, I'm a freelancer.
但这些人在重建它们
But this lot are rebuilding them.
他们利用河流
They've been using the river
通过氢化机挤压 才得到这最终的东西…
extruding them to a flat hydrogen base, so they've got the end result. . .
液态的Huon粒子
Huon particles in liquid form.
那就是在我体内的东西
And that's what's inside me ?
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
天才 因为这些粒子是惰性的
Genius ! Cos the particles are inert.
他们需要一个活体催化媒介 那就是你
They need something living to catalyse inside, and that's you !
充满整个身体 然后…
Saturate the body, then. . .
哦 婚礼
Oh ! The wedding !
是的 你那时快结婚了
Oh ! The wedding ! Yes ! You were getting married !
你生命中最美好的日子…
Best day of your life, walking down the island.
你的身体是个战场 里面是场化学战争
Oh, your body's a battleground. It's a chemical war inside -
肾上腺素 乙酰胆碱 突然来了内啡肽
adrenalin, acetylcholine, wham go the endorphins.
简直是大杂烩
Oh, you're cooking !
你就像个高压锅 一个微波炉
You're like a pressure cooker, a microwave,
全都搅和在一起
all churning away.
粒子终于达到了沸点 哗啦
The particles reach boiling point, shazam !
这次又是为什么
What did I do this time ? !
你说得很开心吗
Are you enjoying this ?
好了 告诉我
Right, just tell me,
这些粒子危险吗
these particles, are they dangerous ?
我安全吗
Am I safe ?
是的
Yes !
博士
Doctor.
如果你们的人除掉了Huon粒子
If your lot got rid of Huon particles,
他们为什么这么做
why did they do that ?
因为这些粒子是致命的
Because they were deadly.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
我发誓 不管对你做了什么 我会逆转它
Whatever's been done to you, I'll reverse it.
我不想再失去任何一个人了
I am not about to lose someone else.
哦 她早就回不来了
Oh, she is long since lost.
我等了那么久
I have waited so long,
在宇宙的边缘冬眠
hibernating at the edge of the universe
直到秘密之心被发现 被唤醒…
until the secret heart was uncovered and called out to waken. . .
有人在这里挖掘过
Someone's been digging.
一看就知道是火炬木 用激光钻的
Oh, very Torchwood. Drilled by laser.
下面有多深
How far down does it go ?
一直往下 直到地球的中心
Down and down. All the way to the centre of the earth.
真的吗
Really ?
说正经的 用来干嘛
Seriously ? What for ?
恐龙 -什么
Dinosaurs. What ?
是恐龙吗
Dinosaurs ?
你在说什么恐龙
What are you on about, dinosaurs ?
那部电影里演的 恐龙
That film, with dinosaurs.
我想帮你忙
I'm trying to help.
别添乱了
That's not helping.
真是甜蜜的一对
Such a sweet couple.
只有疯子才会对着空气说话
Only a madman talks to thin air,
相信我 你不会希望把我惹到发疯的
and trust me, you don't want to make me mad.
你在哪里
Where are you ?
远在天边…
High in the sky. . .
在平安夜的上空漂浮
Floating so high on Christmas night.
我老远来不是来跟对讲机说话的
I didn't come all this way to talk on the intercom.
来吧 让我们看看你
Come on ! Let's have a look at you !
你是谁 敢这样命令我
Who are you, with such command ?
我是博士
I'm The Doctor.
准备好你最好的药吧 医生
Prepare your best medicines, Doctor-man,
因为你的心脏将会受不了的
for you will be sick at heart.
拉贡诺斯
Racnoss.
但那不可能 你是一个拉贡诺斯族人
But that's impossible. You're one of the Racnoss.
拉贡诺斯的女皇
Empress of the Racnoss.
如果你是女皇 那其它的拉贡诺斯呢
If you're the Empress, where's the rest of the Racnoss ?
还是说 只剩你一个了
Or are you the only one ?
脑袋真是敏锐
Such a sharp mind.
对了 你们种族的最后一个了
That's it -the last of your kind.
拉贡诺斯起源于黑暗时代 几十亿以前了
The Racnoss come from the dark times, billions of years ago.
它们是食肉动物 杂食动物 它们能吞掉整个行星
They were carnivores, omnivores, they devoured whole planets.
拉贡诺斯生来就是饥饿的 这是我们的错吗
Racnoss are born starving -is that our fault ?
它们还吃人
They eat people ?
H.C.克莱门斯 他是不是穿着黑白相间的鞋子
HC Clements, did he wear those black and white shoes ?
是的 我们还总笑话他 说他是穿鞋的胖猫
He did. We used to laugh, we used to call him the Fat Cat in Spats.
哦 我的天哪
Oh, my God !
我的圣诞晚餐
My Christmas dinner.
你甚至不该存在
You shouldn't even exist.
很久以前 新生的帝国和拉贡诺斯打仗
Way back in history, the fledglingempires went to war against the Racnoss.
他们被消灭干净了
They were wiped out.
除了我
Except for me.
那就是我身体里的东西 那些个Huon粒子
That's what I've got inside me, that Huon energy thing.
看着我 女士 我在跟你说话
Oi ! Look at me, lady, I'm talking !
我哪里合适了
Where do I fit in ?
我身体里怎么会有这些Huon粒子的
How come I get all stacked up with these Huon particles ?
你 看着我
Look at me, you !
看着我的眼睛告诉我
Look me in the eye and tell me !
新娘脾气很坏
The bride is so feisty !
是的 没错
Yes, I am !
我不知道你是什么 你这个大…东西
And I don't know what you are, you big. . .thing,
但是蜘蛛就是蜘蛛…
but a spider's just a spider. . .
斧子就是斧子
and an axe is an axe,
现在动手
now DO IT !
你刚才的表情真不错
That was a good one. Your face !
兰斯很有趣
Lance is funny.
什么
What ?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
为什么抱歉
Sorry for what ?
兰斯 别愣着 快砍她
Lance, don't be so stupid -get her !
天哪 她真蠢
God, she's thick !
几个月来我都不得不忍受她 好几个月了
Months I've had to put up with her, months !
这女人甚至在地图上连德国都指不出来
A woman who can't even point to Germany on a map !
我不明白
I don't understand.
你怎么遇见他的
How did you meet him ?
在办公室里
In the office.
他给你倒了杯咖啡
He made you coffee.
什么
What ?
每天 我都给你倒咖啡
Every day, I made you coffee.
你服用液态粒子六个多月了
You had to be dosed with liquid particles over six months.
他在给我下毒
He was poisoning me ?
都写在职务的名称上了
It was all there in the job title.
人类资源主管
The head of human resources.
这次 是全体职员
This time, it's personnel.
但是…我们都要结婚了
But. . .we were getting married.
我不能冒险让你跑掉
Well, I couldn't risk you running off !
我只能答应了
I had to say yes.
然后我就被一个有件普林格衣服
Then I was stuck with a woman who
就兴奋地一塌糊涂的女人给缠住了
thinks the height of excitement is a new flavour Pringle !
哦 我还得坐在那里听你那么多废话…
Oh, I had to sit there and listen to all that yap yap yap. . .
哦 布拉德和安吉丽娜… 朴希是不是怀孕了
"Ooh, Brad and Angelina. . . Is Posh pregnant ?
选秀节目 艾特金斯减肥法 风水 头发分叉
"X Factor, Atkins Diet, Feng Shui, split ends,
给我发短信 发短信 发短信…
text me, text me, text me. . ."
天哪 她不停的涌出那些愚蠢的琐事
Dear God, the never-ending fountain of fat, stupid trivia !
我应该得块奖章
I deserve a medal !
那就是她提供给你的 拉贡诺斯女皇
Is that what she's offered you ? The Empress of the Racnoss ?
你是什么 它的情人吗
What are you, her consort ?
总比跟她过一晚上要好
It's better than a night with her.
但是我爱你
But I love you.
这样才让事情变得容易
That's what made it easy.
就像你说的 博士
It's like you said, Doctor.
要放眼大局
The big picture.
如果人类一无是处 那还有什么意义呢
What's the point of it all if the human race is nothing ?
那就是女皇能给我的
That's what the Empress can give me -
有机会走到外面的世界
the chance to go out there,
去看看浩瀚的宇宙
to see it, the size of it all.
我想你能理解 是吧 博士
And I think you understand that, don't you, Doctor ?
这个小医生是谁
Who is this little physician ?
她说是火星人
She said, Martian.
哦 我可以说是无家可归
Oh, I'm sort of homeless.
不过重要的是 下面是什么
But the point is, what's down here ?
拉贡诺斯一族已经灭绝了 4千英里下有什么东西还能帮你
The Racnoss are extinct. What's gonna help you, 4, 000 miles down ?
下面只有地球的液态核心 不是吗
That's just the molten core of the earth.
我认为他要我们谈谈
I think he wants us to talk.
我也这么认为
I think so too.
不必了 我们只需要多娜
Well, tough. All we need is Donna.
杀死这个喋喋不休的小医生
Kill this chattering little Doctor-man.
不许你们伤害他 -不 没关系
Don't you hurt him ! No, it's all right.
不 我不会让他们得逞
I won't let them.
武装
At arms !
现在 只不过
Ah, now. . .except. . .
瞄准
Take aim !
我只想指出显而易见的一点
I just want to point out the obvious.
他们不会打中新娘 他们的枪法很棒
They won't hit the bride, they're such very good shots.
等等…等一秒钟
Just hold on. . . Hold on just a tick,
等小小的一秒钟…一秒钟…
just a tiny little. . .just a tick. . .
你们好好想想
If you think about it,
如果多娜体内的粒子激活了
the particles activated in Donna,
并把她拽到了我的飞船里
and drew her inside my spaceship.
那么反过来
So, reverse it. . .
太空船也能到她这儿来
and the spaceship comes to her !
开火
Fire !
我们出发
And off we go !
钥匙
The key !
我的钥匙
My ke-e-e-ey !
还记得我跟你说过的时间机器吗
Oh. D'you know what you said before,
好吧 我撒了谎
Well, I lied.
现在我们要使用它
And now we're gonna use it.
我们得查出拉贡诺斯女皇在挖什么
We need to find out what the Empress of the Racnoss is digging up.
如果有东西埋在地球核心
If something's buried at the planet's core,
那一定是从一开始就在那里
it must've been there since the beginning.
太棒了 我一直想看看这个
That's just brilliant! I've always wanted to see this.
多娜 我们要回到过去了 我还从来没去过这么久以前
Donna, we're going further back than I've ever been before !
如果钥匙丢了 那就再做一把
If a key is lost, then another must be cut.
武装
At a-a-a-a-arms !
我们到了
We've arrived.
你不想看吗
D'you want to see ?
想吧
Suppose.
等等 显示器有点小 也许你的方法是最好的
Hold on, scanner's a bit small. Maybe your way's best.
来吧
Come on.
还没有人类见过这场面 你是第一个
No human's ever seen this. You'll be the first.
我只想看到我的床
All I want to see is my bed.
多娜·诺博 欢迎…
Donna Noble. Welcome. . .
来到创世之初
to the creation of the Earth.
我们已经回到了46亿年前
We've gone back 4.6 billion years.
还没有太阳系
There's no solar system, not yet.
只有尘埃 岩块和气体
Only dust and rocks and gas.
那是太阳 在那里 崭新的
That's the sun, over there. Brand new.
正开始燃烧
Just beginning to burn.
地球在哪里
Where's the Earth ?
在我们周围
All around us.
在尘埃中
In the dust.
相比之下看看婚礼…
Puts the wedding in perspective.
兰斯是对的 我们太渺小了
Lance was right, we're just. . .tiny.
不 这就是人类的力量
No, but that's what you do, the human race,
从混乱中找出意义
make sense out of chaos.
用婚礼
Marking it out with
圣诞 日历标记每一天
weddings and Christmas and calendars.
这个过程很美 不过前提是有人在看
This whole process is beautiful, but only if it's being observed.
那么我是从这些东西里出来的
So I came out of all this ?
惊叹吧
Isn't that brilliant ?
我觉得那是怀特岛
I think that's the Isle of Wight.
最后 引力占了上风
Eventually, gravity takes hold.
一块大石头 比其他的重 开始把其他石头拉向它
One big rock, heavier than others, starts to pull other rocks towards it.
所有的尘埃 气体和元素都被聚集
All the dust and gas and elements get pulled in,
所有的东西被挤在一起 最后就得到了…
everything piling in, until you get. . .
地球
The Earth.
但问题是
But the question is,
那第一块石头是什么
what was that first rock ?
看…
Look. . .
拉贡诺斯
The Racnoss.
我已经测量了新娘的催化作用
Now I have measured the bride's catalysis,
我可以强行喂食
I can force-feed it.
喝下粒子 成为钥匙吧
Drink the particles, become the key !
等等 拉贡诺斯在躲避战火
Hold on, the Racnoss are hiding from the war.
它在干什么
What's it doing ?
跟你说的一模一样
Exactly what you said !
他们不只是在地球的中心埋了东西
Oh ! They didn't just bury something at the centre of the Earth !
他们成为了地球的中心
They BECAME the centre of the Earth.
第一块岩石
The first rock.
那是什么 -麻烦
What was that ? Trouble.
我的神奇钥匙
My wonderful key !
我的仆人 把他绑起来
Now, my servants, bind him !
它到底在干什么
What the hell's it doing ? !
我的一个小诡计 粒子吸引粒子
That little trick of mine, particles pulling particles
起反作用了 它们要把我们拉回去
it works in reverse. They're pulling us back !
你就不能阻止它吗 这东西没有手刹吗
Well, can't you stop it ? Hasn't it got a handbrake ?
你能不能逆转 或者曲速 传送之类的
Can't you reverse, or, warp, or beam, or something ?
别告诉司机如何开车 等等
Back-seat driver ! Oh ! Wait a minute.
外推器
The extrapolator !
无法停下我们 但应该会给我们一次不错的颠簸
Can't stop us, but should give us a good bump !
新娘将会和新郎一起举行婚礼
The bride shall join her groom
多么盛大的婚礼啊
what a wedding there shall be.
就是现在
Now !
我们向右偏了200码 快点
We've gone about 200 yards to the right. Come on !
她就在这附近 圣洁的新娘
She is close, the holy bride in white !
找到她 找到她
Find her ! Find her !
我们该怎么办
What do we do ? !
我也不知道 边走边想
I don't know ! I'm making it up as I go along.
不过相信我 我有经验
But trust me, I've got history.
但我还是不明白
But I still don't understand.
我浑身充满粒子 要干什么呢
I'm full of particles, but what for ?
地球中心有一个拉贡诺斯蛛网
There's a Racnoss web at the centre of the Earth.
我的族人封印了它们的力量源泉
My people unravelled their power source,
Huon不存在了 拉贡诺斯也就被困在这里了
Hunon particles sealed exists, so the Racnoss were stuck.
他们冬眠了几十亿年 冷冻着 故障着 休眠着
They hibernated for billions of years, frozen, dead, kaput !
而你就是新钥匙 全新的活体粒子
You're the new key -brand-new living particles.
它们需要你开启 而你从未如此安静过
They need you to open it. And you have never been so quiet.
噢
Oh !
我恨你
I hate you.
我认为我们已经说清楚了 甜心
Yeah, I think we've gone a bit beyond that now, sweetheart.
我的好夫妇
My golden couple.
总算团聚了 你们可怕的婚姻生活
Together at last, your awful wedded life.
告诉我 你们想被释放吗
Tell me, do you want to be released ?
想
Yes !
你们应该说"我愿意"
You're supposed to say, "I do."
想也别想
No chance.
快说
Say it !
我愿意 -我愿意
I do. I do.
我…不愿意
I. . .don't !
激活粒子
Activate the particles !
洗涤一切
Purge every last one !
释放吧
And release !
秘密的核心将解封
The Secret Heart unlocks
它们将从万代的沉睡中醒来
and they will waken from their sleep of ages.
它们是谁
Who will ?
那下面是什么
What's down there ?
你真是太蠢了
How thick are you ? !
我的孩子们
My children !
消失已久的拉贡诺斯
The long-lost Racnoss,
现在重生 享受地球的盛宴
now reborn to feast on flesh.
蛛网星即将降临
The Webstar shall come to me.
我的孩子们会饥饿
My babies will be hungry.
它们需要食物
They need sustenance.
不 -解开蛛网
No. . . Perish the web.
用她 不要用我 用她
Use her, not me, use her !
有趣的小兰斯
Oh, my funny little Lance.
但你那样对你女友很不礼貌
But you were quite impolite to your lady-friend.
女皇不赞成
The Empress does not approve.
不
NO !
圣诞节到了
It's Christmas !
收割人类 做成肉酱
Harvest the humans ! Reduce them to meat !
我的孩子们将拥向我 没有人能阻止他们
My children are climbing towards me and none shall stop them !
你也可以脱下面具了 我聪明的小医生
So you might as well unmask, my clever little Doctor-man.
眼力真好
Oh, well, nice try.
我来救你了 多娜
I've got you, Donna.
我要掉下去了 -你会荡过来
I'm gonna fall ! You're gonna swing !
我会接住你的
I've got you.
哦 抱歉
Ooh, sorry.
多谢帮倒忙
Thanks for nothing.
医生逗得我很开心
The Doctor-man amuses me.
拉贡诺斯女皇 我给你最后一次机会
Empress of the Racnoss, I give you one last chance.
我可以给你找一个行星
I can find you a planet,
我可以给你和你的孩子在宇宙找个星球共存
I can find you and your children a place in the universe to co-exist.
接受我的提议 立刻结束这一切
Take that offer, and end this now.
这些人真有趣
These men are so funny !
你的回答是什么
What's your answer ?
恐怕我得拒绝
Oh, I'm afraId I have to decline.
那么接下来发生的事情是你自找的
Then what happens next is your own doing.
我来给你看看接下来会发生什么
I'll show you what happens next !
举枪
At arms !
瞄准
Take aim !
然后…放松
And. . . relax.
你做了什么
What did you do ?
猜猜我有什么 多娜
Guess what I've got, Donna.
口袋
Pockets !
这东西怎么放得下
How did that fit in there ?
里面比外面大
They're bigger on the inside.
机器人不是必需的
Roboforms are not necessary.
我的孩子们会享受火星人的肉
My children may feast on Martian flesh.
但我不是从火星来的
Oh, but I'm not from Mars.
那是哪里
Then where ?
我的家乡非常遥远 而且已经消失很久了
My home planet is far away and long since gone.
但它的名字流传至今
But its name lives on.
伽里弗雷
Gallifrey.
他们杀害了拉贡诺斯
They murdered the Racnoss !
我警告过你
I warned you.
这是你自找的
You did this.
不 不 不要
No ! No ! Don't !
不
NO!
不 不
No ! NO !
不
NO!
NO !
不
不 我的孩子们
NO ! My children !
我的孩子们
My children !
博士
Doctor !
可以停下了
You can stop now.
我的孩子们
My children !
快 我救你出去
Come on. Time I got you out.
传送我
Transport me !
他们会付出代价的 血的代价
Oh, they will suffer, so suffer.
这颗星球将被炙烤
This planet shall be scorched.
那女皇怎么办
But what about the Empress ?
她用尽了所有Huon能量 现在不堪一击
She's used up all her Huon energy -she's defenceless.
Saxon先生的命令 自由开火
Orders from Mr Saxon. Fire at will.
开火
FIRE !
只有一个问题了
There's just one problem.
什么问题
What is it ?
我们抽干了泰晤士河
We've drained the Thames.
看吧 我说过她会没事的
There we go, told you she'd be all right.
什么大难都能幸存
Survive anything.
比我经历的还多
More than I've done.
所有的Huon粒子都消失了
No, all the Huon particles have gone.
没有任何损伤 你没事
No damage. You're fine.
是的 但除此之外
Yeah, but apart from that.
我在同一天错过了婚礼 丢了饭碗 还成了寡妇
I missed my wedding, lost my job, and became a widow on the same day
差不多吧
sort of.
我救不了他
I couldn't save him.
他活该
He deserved it.
不 他不是
No, he didn't.
我最好进去 他们会担心的
Better get inside. They'll be worried.
他们最好的圣诞礼物
Best Christmas present they could have.
哦 不 我忘了 你讨厌圣诞节
Oh, no ! I forgot, you hate Christmas.
没错
Yes, I do.
即使…下雪
Even. . .if it snows ?
不敢相信你能做到这个
I can't believe you did that.
简单的大气刺激
Basic atmospheric excitation.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
你也是
And you.
那么…
So. . .
那你接下来怎么办
what will you do with yourself now ?
首先 不结婚
Not getting married, for starters.
也不当临时工了
And I'm not gonna temp any more.
也许旅行吧
I dunno, travel.
多看看地球
See a bit more of Planet Earth.
游历古迹
Walk in the dust.
走出这里 做点事情
Just go out there and do something.
你其实可以…
Well, you could always. . .
什么
What ?
跟我一起走
Come with me.
不
No.
好的
OK.
我不能
I can't.
不 没关系的
No, that's fine.
真的不行
No, but really.
我们今天发生的一切…
I mean, everything we did today. . .
你的生活一直是这样吗
D'you live your life like that ?
不总是
Not all the time.
我看就是
I think you do.
而我不能
And I couldn't.
你已经看到了外面的世界
You've seen it out there.
它很美
It's beautiful.
也很可怕
And it's terrible.
那里水深火热 人们濒临死亡
That place was flooding, and burning,
而你站在那儿 就像…
and they were dying, and you stood there like. . .
我不知道
I don't know.
一个旁观者
A stranger.
现在你又让这里下雪 差点吓死我了
And then you made it snow. I mean, you scare me to death.
好吧
Well, then.
告诉你我现在要做什么
Tell you what I will do, though.
圣诞晚餐
Christmas dinner.
来吧
Oh, come on !
我不做那一类的事情
I don't do that sort of thing.
你去年做过 你说过的
You did it last year, you said so.
你最好来 因为妈妈做了20人份的大餐
And you might as well, because Mum always cooks enough for 20. Well. . .
好吧 不过你先去 提醒他们一下
Oh, all right, then ! But you go first -better warn them.
但别说我是火星人
And don't say I'm a Martian.
我去把它停好
I just have to park her properly,
否则可能会飘到中世纪去的
she might drift off to the Middle Ages.
回头见
I'll see you in a minute.
博士 博士
Doctor ! DOCTOR !
天哪 你还真能喊
Blimey, you can shout.
我们还会再见面吗
Am I ever going to see you again ?
如果我幸运的话
If I'm lucky.
答应我一件事
Just. . .promise me one thing.
找个同伴
Find someone.
我不需要同伴
I don't need anyone.
你需要
Yes, you do.
因为有时…我觉得需要有人来阻止你
Cos sometimes. . .I think you need someone to stop you.
是啊
Yeah.
谢谢 多娜 祝你好运
Thanks, then, Donna. Good luck.
祝你…
And just. . .
活得精彩
be magnificent.
我想我会的
I think I will, yeah.
博士
Doctor ?
又怎么了
Oh, what is it now ?
你那个朋友 她叫什么名字
That friend of yours. What was her name ?
她叫洛斯
Her name was Rose.
我是博士
I'm The Doctor.
我也是 如果我通过考试的话
Me too, if I ever pass my exams.
你叫什么名字
What was your name ?
玛莎
Martha.
玛莎·琼斯
Martha Jones.
洛斯 并不是说你要替代她
Rose, not that you are replacing her.
我又没说我会
I never said I would.
怪物 有怪物
Monsters! There are monsters !
开始了
It's started.
抱歉
Sorry.
放开她
Let her go !
环球剧场
The Globe Theatre.
莎士比亚先生 对吧
Mr Shakespeare, isn't it ?
你站在这儿干什么 快走啊
What are you standing there for ? Come on !
作为一个搭便车的人 你们穿得很体面
Very well dressed for a hitch-hiker.
不
NO !
别放手
Don't let go !
今晚 我要上演一出奇迹
Tonight, I am going to perform a miracle.
我76岁了
I am 76 years old.